[{"question":"A series resonant circuit is commonly called a tank circuit.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"False"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In a series RLC circuit that is operating above the resonant frequency, the current","answers":{"a":"Lags the applied voltage","b":"Leads the applied voltage","c": "Is in phase with the applied voltage", "d": "Is zero"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The impedance at the resonant frequency of a series RLC circuit with L = 20 mH, C = 0.02 μF, and RW = 90 Ω is","answers":{"a":"0 Ω","b":"90 Ω","c":"20 Ω","d":"40 Ω"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"A 24 Ω resistor, an inductor with a reactance of 120 Ω, and a capacitor with a reactance of 120 Ω are in series across a 60 V source. The circuit is at resonance. The voltage across the inductor is","answers":{"a":"60 V","b":"660 V","c":"30 V","d":"300 V"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The reactive voltages, $V_L$ and $V_C$, cancel at resonance.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"False"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In a series RLC circuit, the current is minimum at resonance.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"False"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"A certain series resonant circuit has a bandwidth of 2 kHz. If the existing coil is replaced with one having a higher value of Q, the bandwidth will","answers":{"a":"Increase","b":"Remain the same","c":"Decrease","d":"Be less selective"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"If the value of C in a series RLC circuit is decreased, the resonant frequency increases","answers":{"a":"True","b":"false"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The power factor of a series RLC circuit at resonance is","answers":{"a":"0.7","b":"0.5","c":"0","d":"1"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"The Quality factor ‘Q’ is equal to _______, and it is an indicator of the sharpness of the resonance in a RLC circuit.","answers":{"a":"ω<sub>0</sub>R/L","b":" ω<sub>O</sub>L/R","c":"LR/ω<sub>O</sub>","d":"LRω<sub>O</sub>"},"correctAnswer":"b"}]
